Guide to the Sheldon Moore Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Sheldon Moore papers
1815-1846
MS 992
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
0.25
The papers consist of correspondence and notebooks relating to Sheldon Moore's family in Southington, Connecticut, and his studies at Yale University.
Moore, Sheldon, 1798-1866
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Purchased in 1956.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
These papers consist of letters and notebooks belonging to Sheldon Moore of Southington, Connecticut. Among the letters are one from Moore to his wife and one to friends and family in Southington, one to Moore from his father, one from a brother, and two from his wife. There is also one letter from Moore's wife to their son John, and one to her from an unidentified person. All of these letters deal with the family's health and daily activities. There are, in addition, three letters to Moore from friends and business acquaintances.
Of Moore's five notebooks, two are diary and expense books covering the years 1815-1816 and 1819-1822, one is a commonplace book, one contains short essays, notes on marriages and deaths in Southington, and lists of books, and the last volume contains notes on Euclidian geometry and dates from Moore's study at Yale College. The final item in the collection is a chart comparing the size, population, government, and other aspects of the states of the Union, probably made while Moore was a student.
Biographical / Historical
Sheldon Moore was born in Southington, Connecticut, on October 17, 1798. He was the son of Roswell and Lovina (Phillips) Moore, and was born in Southington, Conn., Oct. 17, 1798. He graduated from Yale in 1818. After his graduation he taught for some time in Virginia and in Connecticut. He afterwards studied law, and was admitted to the bar, but did not make it his profession. He was engaged in business from which he retired about twenty-five years ago, on account of a failure of health. Sheldon Moore died in Kensington, Conn., March 20, 1866, aged 67 years.
(Taken from Yale Obituary Record, 1860-70, p. 202).
Families; Connecticut; Southington (Conn.) -- Description and travel; Moore, Sheldon, 1798-1866; Yale University -- Students
- Inventory
  - Family letters
    - O. Moore: ALS to his brother, Sheldon Moore, 1820 July 13 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Roswell Moore: ALS to his son, Sheldon Moore, 1819 December 8 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Sheldon Moore
      - ALS to family and friends in Southington, 1819 February 9 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - ALS to his wife, Susan L. Dickinson (Moore), 1831 August 13 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Susan L. (Dickinson) Moore
      - 2 ALS to Sheldon Moore, 1845 January 9, 1846 March 25 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - ALS to son John Moore, 1846 March 26 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Other letters
    - 3 ALS to Sheldon Moore from friends and others, 1819-1820 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - ALS to Susan L. (Dickinson) Moore from unidentified, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notebooks
    - "Euclid's Elements of Geometry", 1815 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Diary and expense book, 1815-1816 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Volume of essays, notes on marriages and deaths, etc., 1815-1826 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Commonplace book, 1816-1822 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Diary and expense book, 1819-1822 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Chart comparing states, [pre-1816] (Box 1, Folder 4)